Hello everyone and welcome
to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today we have an
elementary level lesson about
things that you buy for your kitchen.
That's right, today
we are going to buy a
lot of machines and
devices for our kitchen.
So let's jump into
the dialogue, let's see
what we are buying
and we'll be back in a bit.
I have been looking
at this online catalog
for over an hour and
I still haven't finished
getting all the kitchen
appliances that we need.
What are you getting?
Well, the first thing on
my list is a new blender.
I decided to also get a
juicer and a new coffee maker.
Don't forget to also get a new mixer.
I lent the old one to my
brother and he broke it.
Yeah, I know.
I also decided to throw away
the old toaster and get a new one.
I am also getting a rice
cooker and a steamer
to make some nice
steamed fish or veggies.
I'm actually thinking
of completely refinishing
the kitchen and getting a new stove,
oven, dishwasher and trash compactor.
That's a good idea.
The kitchen will look amazing.
All right, we're back.
So now let's take a look at some of those
strange machines on language takeaway.
Okay, so the kinds of machines you buy for
your kitchen are called kitchen appliances.
Okay, so the word appliance
in appliance is basically
a machine or device that
is used for the home, right?
That's right.
So there are many
different kinds of appliances.
You can usually plug these in.
They usually need
electricity to work, but the
ones we're talking
about today are special.
They're for the kitchen.
So that's why we call
them kitchen appliances.
That's right.
Okay, very good.
So the kitchen appliances
that we are looking
at or we're trying to buy is, well, the
first one we have is a blender, a blender.
So a blender is a kitchen appliance
that you use normally to make drinks.
So this is a glass jar that's usually
on the top of a little machine.
When you put in, for example, some ice and
some tea and some lemonade and you can mix
it up and you have
this special mixed drink.
So it's called a blender.
That's right.
So as you mentioned, it's usually
used to make some sort of juice or drink.
But we also are getting a juicer,
which is specifically to make juices.
Now what is the difference
between the blender and a juicer?
Well, a blender is a machine that
turns the things inside it around.
So it mixes them together.
But a juicer is different
because a juicer
will actually take the
juice from the fruit.
So for example, if I
have an orange and I cut
the orange in half, I
put that half on the
juicer and it turns around so
that the juice will come down.
Because otherwise, I have to use my
hands to squeeze it and that takes time.
So this is an electronic appliance that
helps me get the juice from my fruits.
That's right.
Okay.
So the juicer to make
juice, a blender to
make different drinks,
and now to make coffee,
we have a very simple
machine, a coffee maker.
Okay.
So a coffee maker is
just a simple machine
that you put water and coffee into
and it will make the coffee for you.
Usually it's called a drip coffee maker
because the coffee drip, drip, drip, down.
But there are many different
kinds of coffee makers.
Okay.
Now, this next
appliance can be a little
bit confusing because now
this one is called a mixer.
So what is the difference between a
blender, a juicer, and now we have a mixer?
Well, there are
different kinds of mixers
actually, but usually the kind of mixer
that we were referring to that we're talking
about is one that is
electronic and it looks
like it has these two
funny spoons on the end.
And when you turn
the mixer on, you put it
into a bowl and you mix
the things in the bowl.
So for example, if I
want to make pancakes,
I put some flour and
some water and some eggs
into a bowl and I could stir it with my
hand, with my spoon, but it's very tiring.
So there's a mixer that's electronic to
turn those ingredients around on its own.
That's right.
So it's quicker and obviously
you don't get as tired.
Very good.
So I think we should take a break.
Let's go back to our dialogue.
Let's check out some
more appliances and
we'll be back to talk
about the rest of them.
I have been looking
at this online catalog
for over an hour and
I still haven't finished
getting all the kitchen
appliances that we need.
What are you getting?
Well, the first thing on
my list is a new blender.
I decided to also get a
juicer and a new coffee maker.
Don't forget to also get a new mixer.
I lent the old one to my
brother and he broke it.
Yeah, I know.
I also decided to throw away
the old toaster and get a new one.
I am also getting a rice
cooker and a steamer
to make some nice
steamed fish or veggies.
I'm actually thinking
of completely refinishing
the kitchen and getting a new stove,
oven, dishwasher and trash compactor.
That's a good idea.
The kitchen will look amazing.
All right, we're back.
So now let's take a look at more kitchen
appliances on language takeaway part two.
Change takeaway.
Well this first item,
this first appliance is
something that I know a lot of people
all over the world are familiar with.
It's called a rice cooker.
Now a rice cooker, as the
name says, it is used to cook
rice, but it doesn't in a very
simple and automatic way.
That's right.
So you put the rice and the water and
the rice cooker and you turn it on to what?
20 minutes and then later, 20
minutes later, it's already cooked.
It's done.
Really?
Right.
It's actually very convenient
and very simple to make.
And now along with a rice cooker,
sometimes we also get a steamer.
Okay, so a steamer
is something that we
normally use with
vegetables or in Asia a lot of
times we use it with dumplings,
these little foods that are stuffed.
And so a steamer is
something that you use to
cook a food, but with
the steam from hot water.
That's right.
You don't fry the food, but you use the
steam that hot air to cook the food inside.
That's right.
So it's actually considered
to be some of the one of the
healthiest ways of cooking
food because it's not as oily.
That's right.
Okay.
So now an interesting
appliance that is actually
not very popular in
any other place except
I mean, think North
America is a trash compactor.
Okay.
So a trash means
garbage, it's the things that
you want to throw away
that you won't use anymore.
And a compactor is something that actually
takes the trash and it makes it very small.
Okay.
Compact means small.
And so a trash compactor
is like a special garbage bin.
You put your garbage
in it and you close it
and you say compact and
then it makes a loud noise.
Oh.
That's right.
And then when you
pull it out, you open it up.
The trash is very, very small.
Very small.
So it's very easy to throw away.
So as we said, I've
never actually seen this
appliance in any other country
except the United States and Canada.
I don't think I have
either, but it's pretty
popular in American
homes because it helps
save space and it's very easy
to throw things away that way.
Yeah.
That's right.
I guess you can make
a little bundle of trash
and it's much easier than
throwing a big bag of trash away.
Exactly.
Okay.
And well, we're doing all this because
we are kind of refinishing the kitchen.
We are giving it new furniture.
That's right.
So we want to change the appearance
and to do this, we will refurnish.
So to furnish something means to
put furniture in it to make it look nice.
To refurnish means to change the
furniture because we already have some.
We don't like it.
That's right.
And so you can do this
with your whole house.
That's right.
So maybe you throw
away the old couch and
the table and the kitchen
cabinet and you put a new one.
So you are refinishing your
home, refinishing the kitchen.
That's right.
To refurnish.
Okay.
A lot of great vocab here.
I think this is very
useful for the kitchen,
especially if sometimes
you don't really
know what appliance you need to buy
or what the instructions of a recipe say.
So why don't we listen to the
dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
I have been looking
at this online catalog
for over an hour and
I still haven't finished
getting all the kitchen
appliances that we need.
What are you getting?
Well, the first thing on
my list is a new blender.
I decided to also get a
juicer and a new coffee maker.
Don't forget to also get a new mixer.
I lent the old one to my
brother and he broke it.
Yeah, I know.
I also decided to throw away
the old toaster and get a new one.
I am also getting a rice
cooker and a steamer
to make some nice
steamed fish or veggies.
I'm actually thinking of
completely refurnishing
the kitchen and getting a new stove,
oven, dishwasher and trash compactor.
That's a good idea.
The kitchen will look amazing.
All right, we're back.
Now another appliance that I think is
also not very popular in other countries.
Apart from the trash compactor,
we saw in the dialogue a dishwasher.
A dishwasher, that's right.
So this is something that you
find in many American homes.
So why do you think
trash compactors and
dishwashers are not so
popular in other places?
I'm not sure.
It's possible it's because
they're not very energy efficient.
I'm not really sure.
I never had a trash compactor in my home
in America, but we always had a dishwasher.
And this was very, very
nice to have because
you don't have to wash
the dishes by yourself.
You put them in the machine
and the machine washes.
But you have to do some work
before you put the dishes in dishwasher.
You have to put them in the
sink and water for a while and
then you take them out and then
you put them in the dishwasher.
Now what we usually
did is if there was food
on a plate, we take the food
and we put it in the trash.
And if it's, you know,
sometimes you leave
the plate for like a day
or two and it's very hard.
Then you have to put
some water on it because
otherwise it will be hard
and it will never come off.
But if it's recently used, you put all the
plates, all of the cups, all of the knives
and forks into the
dishwasher and it uses hot
water and some soap and it will
wash those dishes in about 30 minutes.
So how well does it wash?
It washes very, very well.
Some work better than
others but of course if you have
food that's two days old on
a plate then I won't wash it.
I think it also has to
do with the type of
instruments that people
use around the world to cook.
For example, big pots.
I don't think you can put
pots in the dishwasher, right?
No, you can't.
You could not put a wok in the dishwasher.
But I think it also has to do with
the fact that dishwashers are very big.
And if you have a small
apartment or like me a very small
kitchen, it's impossible to
make room for a dishwasher.
But it seems like a
very convenient thing
and of course there are so many other kitchen
appliances that, well if we started to
mention all of them,
we would run out of time.
But if you have any
questions or comments
about this lesson or you
have maybe some other
kitchen appliances, you can
come to our website www.
EnglishPod.com
and leave those there.
We hope to see you at
EnglishPod and until next time.
Bye.
[Music]